# **Martin Haensch**

Menlo Park, CA ✓ Eligibility: Eligible to work in the U.S. Personal website: https://mhansch.com/

+1 (650) 223-3141 haenschmartin@gmail.com 🖂 https://www.linkedin.com/in/martin-haensch/



### **SUMMARY**

I am a motivated, reliable, and dedicated German Automation Engineer and Full Stack Software Developer with 5+ years of professional experience. I recently moved to the US and have been waiting for my work permit, which I have now received. Therefore, I am now looking for new professional challenges and development opportunities in the Bay Area. Particularly, I am passionate about IoT, renewable energy systems, and anything that helps making the world a better and more connected place.

# **EDUCATION**

## **University of Applied Sciences Mittelhessen (THM)**

Giessen, Germany

10/2014 - 05/2018

**Degree**: Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical and Information Technology / Automation Engineer)

Algorithms and Data Structures, Web Development, Databases, Front-End Engineer, Design Patterns

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Fullstack Software Developer** In cooperation with TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

05/2018 - 08/2020

smart.ModoCorrente (http://cloudswitching.de): Cloud-based PLC controlling system / smart home for industrial purposes

The idea to develop this product was based on my bachelor thesis. The product development was sponsored by the company TeDatCo GmbH, where I acted as a Software Engineer and business partner during this time.

- Front- & backend programming of a smart home application for industrial purposes including the following tasks:
- Programming a functional PLC (S7-1200) which connects to an external server (SCL in TIA-Portal)
- Programming external interfaces to handle connections between the database and the PLC (C#)
- Handling structures of the database (MongoDB)
- Programming a customer friendly website to control PLC outputs (PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
- Active documentation of the processes and training new staff
- Success parameters: Originally developed for renewable energy facilities, smart. Modo Corrente launched on the German market in 2019 and optimizes maintenance while reducing downtime by up to 100% for customers in various industries. Reported savings from current customers up to 600k Euros.

Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AJAX, PHP, C#, MongoDB, TIA Portal, TCP/IP, Git

# **Automation Engineer**

# TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

05/2018 - 08/2020

ModoCorrente (www.modoCorrente.de): System for remote control for renewable energy (wind, solar)

- Planning and installing control systems for renewable energy components (e.g., wind turbines)
- Creating networks for communication of diverse components (Ethernet, fieldbus)
- Splicing of glass fibres (9μm 62,5μm) inclusive attenuating measurements of glass fibres
- Preparing technical drawings and Handling circuit diagrams
- Mounting control cabinet including on-site troubleshooting
- PLC Programming (Siemens S7-Series)

Utilized: TIA Portal, SPlan, Network technologies, Antenna technology, GSM, Bus Protocols, Glass fiber technologies

# **Data Analyst**

# Philipps University Marburg, Germany

01/2017 - 01/2018

- Preparing and processing physiological data sets, e.g. with excel or Python
- Scripting and facilitating data management for research staff

Utilized: MS Excel, VBA, Python

### **Student Trainee** TeDatCo GmbH, Germany

10/2015 - 05/2018

Energy Timetable: VBA programmed automatic timetable.

- Programming VBA-Excel applications for automated energy tables for large industrial companies
- Soldering control boards and selecting & wiring electrical components

Utilized: MS Excel, VBA

**Vocational Training / Office Manager** 

PMCS GmbH & Co. KG, Germany

08/2009 - 06/2012

Military Service (Joint Medical Service) German Military, Germany

07/2007 - 05/2009

# **OTHER PROJECTS**

"Bartists" (in progress): Platform to connect bars and artists

Full stack web development project including frontend, backend, and design Utilized: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, PHP, Laravel, MySQL

"Plantguard" (smart home application): Controller to water plants automatically

Programming a NodeESP-Board with sensors and actors to water plants automatically

Utilized: Arduino Software, C